So now we will see the concept of Mifare classic 4K structure.
So we will start with the memory structure.
So 4K cards have 4096 bytes of total memory.
And this memory is divided into 40 sectors starting from zero till 39.
So it's quite similar to Mifare classic one K structure.
The 32 the first 32 sectors starting from zero till 31 are of four blocks.
As it's quite similar to the classic one K structure.
So 3232 sectors starting from zero till 31 are of four blocks and the remaining eight sectors are of
16 blocks.
This is the only difference.
We will see this in the diagram in a moment.
But the eight sectors are of 16 blocks.
This is the only difference.
Each sector has a sector trailer as before.
The 1K1K also has.
Each sector has a sector trailer and it's similar to the authentication as well.
Authentication is required in 4k structure as well.
So let's just see this diagram.
So measure classic 4K starting from sector zero till 31.
Over here, you can see 31 out of four blocks starting from zero till three.
So altogether four blocks after 31 starting from 32.
Each block is of sorry.
Each sector is of 16 blocks, starting from zero till 15.
As you can see, if you need bigger memory for some reason you can you can use these 4K cards as well.
But in my opinion, one K cards are enough because there are 16 blocks sorry, in 16 sectors in one
K as well.
So you can use a single card, one k card in 16 places like you can use sector four for your garage
and sector five for your library access.
Similarly, sector eight, you can use it for your door access control and and so on.
So one k is enough, but there is 4k as well for bigger projects as well.
Right?
So this is the memory structure of 4k cards.